<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE html
  PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.1 plus MathML 2.0//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/MathML2/dtd/xhtml-math11-f.dtd">
<html
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
	xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
><head><title>GLUT</title><link rel="stylesheet" href="style.css" type="text/css"/><meta name="generator" content="DocBook XSL Stylesheets V1.59.1"/><link rel="home" href="index.xml" title="PyOpenGL 2.0.1.09 Man Pages"/><link rel="up" href="reference.xml" title="Part I. Reference"/><link rel="previous" href="gluUnProject4.3G.xml" title="gluUnProject4"/><link rel="next" href="glut.3GLUT.xml" title="glut"/></head><body bgcolor="white" text="black" link="#0000FF" vlink="#840084" alink="#0000FF"><div class="navheader"><table width="100%" summary="Navigation header"><tr><th colspan="3" align="center">GLUT</th></tr><tr><td width="20%" align="left"><a accesskey="p" href="gluUnProject4.3G.xml">Prev</a> </td><th width="60%" align="center">Part I. Reference</th><td width="20%" align="right"> <a accesskey="n" href="glut.3GLUT.xml">Next</a></td></tr></table><hr/></div><div class="reference" lang="en"><a name="reference-GLUT"/><div class="titlepage"><div><h1 class="title"><a name="reference-GLUT"/>GLUT</h1></div><hr/></div><div class="toc"><p><b>Table of Contents</b></p><dl><dt><a href="glut.3GLUT.xml">glut</a> - an introduction to the OpenGL Utility Toolkit</dt><dt><a href="glutAddMenuEntry.3GLUT.xml">glutAddMenuEntry</a> - adds a menu entry to the bottom of the current menu.</dt><dt><a href="glutAddSubMenu.3GLUT.xml">glutAddSubMenu</a> - adds a sub-menu trigger to the bottom of the current menu.</dt><dt><a href="glutAttachMenu.3GLUT.xml">glutAttachMenu</a> - attaches/detaches a mouse button for the current window to the identifier of the current menu</dt><dt><a href="glutBitmapCharacter.3GLUT.xml">glutBitmapCharacter</a> - renders a bitmap character using OpenGL.</dt><dt><a href="glutBitmapWidth.3GLUT.xml">glutBitmapWidth</a> - returns the width/length of a bitmap character/string.</dt><dt><a href="glutButtonBoxFunc.3GLUT.xml">glutButtonBoxFunc</a> - sets the dial &amp; button box button callback for the current window.</dt><dt><a href="glutChangeToMenuEntry.3GLUT.xml">glutChangeToMenuEntry</a> - changes the specified menu item in the current menu into a menu entry.</dt><dt><a href="glutChangeToSubMenu.3GLUT.xml">glutChangeToSubMenu</a> - changes the specified menu item in the current menu into a sub-menu trigger.</dt><dt><a href="glutCopyColormap.3GLUT.xml">glutCopyColormap</a> - copies the logical colormap for the layer in use from a specified window to the current window.</dt><dt><a href="glutCreateMenu.3GLUT.xml">glutCreateMenu</a> - creates a new pop-up menu.</dt><dt><a href="glutCreateSubWindow.3GLUT.xml">glutCreateSubWindow</a> - creates a subwindow.</dt><dt><a href="glutCreateWindow.3GLUT.xml">glutCreateWindow</a> - creates a top-level window.</dt><dt><a href="glutDestroyMenu.3GLUT.xml">glutDestroyMenu</a> - destroys the specified menu.</dt><dt><a href="glutDestroyWindow.3GLUT.xml">glutDestroyWindow</a> - destroys the specified window.</dt><dt><a href="glutDeviceGet.3GLUT.xml">glutDeviceGet</a> - retrieves GLUT device information represented by integers.</dt><dt><a href="glutDialsFunc.3GLUT.xml">glutDialsFunc</a> - sets the dial &amp; button box dials callback for the current window.</dt><dt><a href="glutDisplayFunc.3GLUT.xml">glutDisplayFunc</a> - sets the display callback for the current window.</dt><dt><a href="glutEnterGameMode.3GLUT.xml">glutEnterGameMode</a> - enters and leaves GLUT's game mode.</dt><dt><a href="glutEntryFunc.3GLUT.xml">glutEntryFunc</a> - sets the mouse enter/leave callback for the current window.</dt><dt><a href="glutEstablishOverlay.3GLUT.xml">glutEstablishOverlay</a> - establishes an overlay (if possible) for the current window.</dt><dt><a href="glutExtensionSupported.3GLUT.xml">glutExtensionSupported</a> - helps to easily determine whether a given OpenGL extension is supported.</dt><dt><a href="glutForceJoystickFunc.3GLUT.xml">glutForceJoystickFunc</a> - forces current window's joystick callback to be called.</dt><dt><a href="glutFullScreen.3GLUT.xml">glutFullScreen</a> - requests that the current window be made full screen.</dt><dt><a href="glutGameModeGet.3GLUT.xml">glutGameModeGet</a> - retrieves GLUT game mode information represented by integers.</dt><dt><a href="glutGameModeString.3GLUT.xml">glutGameModeString</a> - sets the game mode configuration via a string.</dt><dt><a href="glutGet.3GLUT.xml">glutGet</a> - retrieves simple GLUT state represented by integers.</dt><dt><a href="glutGetColor.3GLUT.xml">glutGetColor</a> - retrieves a red, green, or blue component for a given color index colormap entry for the layer in use's logical
		colormap for the current window.</dt><dt><a href="glutGetModifiers.3GLUT.xml">glutGetModifiers</a> - returns the modifier key state when certain callbacks were generated.</dt><dt><a href="glutIdleFunc.3GLUT.xml">glutIdleFunc</a> - sets the global idle callback.</dt><dt><a href="glutIgnoreKeyRepeat.3GLUT.xml">glutIgnoreKeyRepeat</a> - determines if auto repeat keystrokes are reported to the current window</dt><dt><a href="glutInit.3GLUT.xml">glutInit</a> - initialize the GLUT library.</dt><dt><a href="glutInitDisplayMode.3GLUT.xml">glutInitDisplayMode</a> - sets the initial display mode.</dt><dt><a href="glutInitDisplayString.3GLUT.xml">glutInitDisplayString</a> - sets the initial display mode via a string.</dt><dt><a href="glutInitWindowPosition.3GLUT.xml">glutInitWindowPosition</a> - set the initial window position and size respectively.</dt><dt><a href="glutJoystickFunc.3GLUT.xml">glutJoystickFunc</a> - sets the joystick callback for the current window.</dt><dt><a href="glutKeyboardFunc.3GLUT.xml">glutKeyboardFunc</a> - sets the keyboard callback for the current window.</dt><dt><a href="glutKeyboardUpFunc.3GLUT.xml">glutKeyboardUpFunc</a> - sets the keyboard up (key release) callback for the current window.</dt><dt><a href="glutLayerGet.3GLUT.xml">glutLayerGet</a> - retrieves GLUT state pertaining to the layers of the current window.</dt><dt><a href="glutMainLoop.3GLUT.xml">glutMainLoop</a> - enters the GLUT event processing loop.</dt><dt><a href="glutMenuStatusFunc.3GLUT.xml">glutMenuStatusFunc</a> - sets the global menu status callback.</dt><dt><a href="glutMotionFunc.3GLUT.xml">glutMotionFunc</a> - set the motion and passive motion callbacks respectively for the current window.</dt><dt><a href="glutMouseFunc.3GLUT.xml">glutMouseFunc</a> - sets the mouse callback for the current window.</dt><dt><a href="glutOverlayDisplayFunc.3GLUT.xml">glutOverlayDisplayFunc</a> - sets the overlay display callback for the current window.</dt><dt><a href="glutPopWindow.3GLUT.xml">glutPopWindow</a> - change the stacking order of the current window relative to its siblings.</dt><dt><a href="glutPositionWindow.3GLUT.xml">glutPositionWindow</a> - requests a change to the position of the current window.</dt><dt><a href="glutPostOverlayRedisplay.3GLUT.xml">glutPostOverlayRedisplay</a> - marks the overlay of the current or specified window as needing to be redisplayed.</dt><dt><a href="glutPostRedisplay.3GLUT.xml">glutPostRedisplay</a> - marks the current or specified window as needing to be redisplayed.</dt><dt><a href="glutRemoveMenuItem.3GLUT.xml">glutRemoveMenuItem</a> - remove the specified menu item.</dt><dt><a href="glutRemoveOverlay.3GLUT.xml">glutRemoveOverlay</a> - removes the overlay (if one exists) from the current window.</dt><dt><a href="glutReportErrors.3GLUT.xml">glutReportErrors</a> - for debugging purposes; prints out OpenGL run-time errors.</dt><dt><a href="glutReshapeFunc.3GLUT.xml">glutReshapeFunc</a> - sets the reshape callback for the current window.</dt><dt><a href="glutReshapeWindow.3GLUT.xml">glutReshapeWindow</a> - requests a change to the size of the current window.</dt><dt><a href="glutSetColor.3GLUT.xml">glutSetColor</a> - sets the color of a colormap entry in the layer of use for the current window.</dt><dt><a href="glutSetCursor.3GLUT.xml">glutSetCursor</a> - changes the cursor image of the current window.</dt><dt><a href="glutSetKeyRepeat.3GLUT.xml">glutSetKeyRepeat</a> - sets the key repeat mode</dt><dt><a href="glutSetMenu.3GLUT.xml">glutSetMenu</a> - set/get the current menu</dt><dt><a href="glutSetWindow.3GLUT.xml">glutSetWindow</a> - set/get the current window</dt><dt><a href="glutSetWindowTitle.3GLUT.xml">glutSetWindowTitle</a> - change the window or icon title respectively of the current top-level window.</dt><dt><a href="glutShowOverlay.3GLUT.xml">glutShowOverlay</a> - shows or hides the overlay of the current window</dt><dt><a href="glutShowWindow.3GLUT.xml">glutShowWindow</a> - change the display status of the current window.</dt><dt><a href="glutSolidCone.3GLUT.xml">glutSolidCone</a> - render a solid or wireframe cone respectively.</dt><dt><a href="glutSolidCube.3GLUT.xml">glutSolidCube</a> - render a solid or wireframe cube respectively.</dt><dt><a href="glutSolidDodecahedron.3GLUT.xml">glutSolidDodecahedron</a> - render a solid or wireframe dodecahedron (12-sided regular solid) respectively.</dt><dt><a href="glutSolidIcosahedron.3GLUT.xml">glutSolidIcosahedron</a> - render a solid or wireframe icosahedron (20-sided regular solid) respectively.</dt><dt><a href="glutSolidOctahedron.3GLUT.xml">glutSolidOctahedron</a> - render a solid or wireframe octahedron (8-sided regular solid) respectively.</dt><dt><a href="glutSolidSphere.3GLUT.xml">glutSolidSphere</a> - render a solid or wireframe sphere respectively.</dt><dt><a href="glutSolidTeapot.3GLUT.xml">glutSolidTeapot</a> - render a solid or wireframe teapot respectively.</dt><dt><a href="glutSolidTetrahedron.3GLUT.xml">glutSolidTetrahedron</a> - render a solid or wireframe tetrahedron (4-sided regular solid) respectively.</dt><dt><a href="glutSolidTorus.3GLUT.xml">glutSolidTorus</a> - render a solid or wireframe torus (doughnut) respectively.</dt><dt><a href="glutSpaceballButtonFunc.3GLUT.xml">glutSpaceballButtonFunc</a> - sets the Spaceball button callback for the current window.</dt><dt><a href="glutSpaceballMotionFunc.3GLUT.xml">glutSpaceballMotionFunc</a> - sets the Spaceball motion callback for the current window.</dt><dt><a href="glutSpaceballRotateFunc.3GLUT.xml">glutSpaceballRotateFunc</a> - sets the Spaceball rotation callback for the current window.</dt><dt><a href="glutSpecialFunc.3GLUT.xml">glutSpecialFunc</a> - sets the special keyboard callback for the current window.</dt><dt><a href="glutSpecialUpFunc.3GLUT.xml">glutSpecialUpFunc</a> - sets the special keyboard up (key release) callback for the current window.</dt><dt><a href="glutStrokeCharacter.3GLUT.xml">glutStrokeCharacter</a> - renders a stroke character using OpenGL.</dt><dt><a href="glutStrokeWidth.3GLUT.xml">glutStrokeWidth</a> - returns the width/length of a stroke character/string.</dt><dt><a href="glutSwapBuffers.3GLUT.xml">glutSwapBuffers</a> - swaps the buffers of the current window if double buffered.</dt><dt><a href="glutTabletButtonFunc.3GLUT.xml">glutTabletButtonFunc</a> - sets the special keyboard callback for the current window.</dt><dt><a href="glutTabletMotionFunc.3GLUT.xml">glutTabletMotionFunc</a> - sets the special keyboard callback for the current window.</dt><dt><a href="glutTimerFunc.3GLUT.xml">glutTimerFunc</a> - registers a timer callback to be triggered in a specified number of milliseconds.</dt><dt><a href="glutUseLayer.3GLUT.xml">glutUseLayer</a> - changes the layer in use for the current window.</dt><dt><a href="glutVideoResizeGet.3GLUT.xml">glutVideoResizeGet</a> - retrieves GLUT video resize information represented by integers.</dt><dt><a href="glutVisibilityFunc.3GLUT.xml">glutVisibilityFunc</a> - sets the visibility callback for the current window.</dt><dt><a href="glutWarpPointer.3GLUT.xml">glutWarpPointer</a> - </dt><dt><a href="glutWindowStatusFunc.3GLUT.xml">glutWindowStatusFunc</a> - sets the window status callback for the current window.</dt></dl></div></div><div class="navfooter"><hr/><table width="100%" summary="Navigation footer"><tr><td width="40%" align="left"><a accesskey="p" href="gluUnProject4.3G.xml">Prev</a> </td><td width="20%" align="center"><a accesskey="u" href="reference.xml">Up</a></td><td width="40%" align="right"> <a accesskey="n" href="glut.3GLUT.xml">Next</a></td></tr><tr><td width="40%" align="left" valign="top">gluUnProject4 </td><td width="20%" align="center"><a accesskey="h" href="index.xml">Home</a></td><td width="40%" align="right" valign="top"> glut</td></tr></table></div></body></html>